Linda S. Schwartz Papers VHP2004/16
CCSU Veterans History Project
Linda S. Schwartz Papers
Bulk, 1967-1986
December 1967 - November 1986, 2004
VHP2004/16
CCSU Veterans History Project
17.0 Digital objects 1 interview DVD
Schwartz, Linda S., (Linda Spoonster), 1944 -
Biographical/Historical note
Linda Schwartz enlisted in the U.S. Air Force in 1967, after graduating from nursing school. One reason she joined was an article she had read in Reader's Digest about flight nurses. She went to Sheppard Field (TX) and Amarillo (TX) for training before being assigned to Tachikawa Air Force Base in Japan. This is where many of the wounded soldiers from Vietnam recuperated before being sent back to the United States. It was there, caring for the wounded, that she decided to make the Air Force a career. When she returned from Japan, she was stationed at Plattsburg Air Force Base (NY), and then later went to Brooks Air Force Base (TX) in 1971, to train to be a flight nurse. Schwartz then went to Germany where she was a flight nurse at Rhein-Main. From Germany they flew missions across Europe, the Middle East, and Russia, transporting up to 60 patients per plane. After eight years in Germany, Schwartz returned to the United States, and was recruited to work at McGuire Air Force Base (NJ)" It was there that she was injured while flying a training mission in 1983. She was medically discharged from the Air Force in 1986, and joined the Vietnam Veterans of America. She has been a Commissioner of Veterans Affairs in Connecticut since 2003.
Conditions Governing Access note
Open for Research
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
Technical metadata of digital objects are extracted and encoded in PREMIS preservation metadata format
Preservation Metadata
Custodial History note
All manuscripts and photographs donated were digitized and digitally preserved. The donor retained all original manuscripts and photographs.
Online Access
An online exhibition of this veteran's papers can be accessed at project's website
Arrangement note
This collection is arranged based on content and material type into 3 series:
Series I, Personal papers
Series II, Publications
Series III, Multi-media
United States. Air Force Nurse Corps.; Amarillo (Tex.); McGuire Air Force Base (N.J.); Rhein-Main Air Base (Germany); Sheppard Field (Tex.); Tachikawa-shi (Japan); Vietnam War, 1961-1975 -- Personal narrative, American; Vietnam War, 1961-1975 -- Women; Women and the military
- Series I: Personal Papers, VHP2004/16.I
  - Interview Sysnopsis, April 15, 2004; VHP2004/16.I.1
- Series II: Publications, VHP2004/16.II
  - Memoirs about my father, Memorials day 2005 (5pages), May 30, 2005; VHP2004/16.II.1; 5.0 Digital objects
- Series III: Multi-Media, VHP2004/16.III
  - Subseries A: Still Images, VHP2004/16.III.a
    - L to R: Cherie Rennie and Linda S. Schwartz; Being sworn into the service, 1967; VHP2004/16.III.1
    - Linda S. Schwartz, 1972, VHP2004/16.III.2
    - Linda S. Schwartz, basic training, circa 1967-1971; VHP2004/16.III.3
    - Linda S. Schwartz; Amarillo Air Force Base, TX, circa 1967 - 1971; VHP2004/16.III.4
    - Linda S. Schwartz in fatigues, circa 1995; VHP2004/16.III.5
    - Linda S. Schwartz (right) on an airplane with a patient, VHP2004/16.III.6
    - Linda S. Schwartz, Flight Nurse, with a patient., Vietnam War era; VHP2004/16.III.7
    - L to R: Chief Nurse of USAF Hospital, Linda S. Schwartz, Commander of USAF Hospital; she got promoted to the rank of captain; Tachikawa, Japan, circa 1967 - 1975; VHP2004/16.III.8
    - Linda S. Schwartz, unknown, Cherie Rennie; home on leave, circa 1967 - 1975; VHP2004/16.III.9
    - Women who served in Vietnam rally, Post 1975; VHP2004/16.III.10
    - Commissioner Linda Spoonster Schwartz at the dedication of the Veterans History Project at Central Connecticut State University, November 21, 2005; VHP2004/16.III.11
  - Subseries B: Moving Images, VHP2004/16.III.b
    - Oral History Interview, April 14, 2004; VHP2004/16.III.b.1; 1.0 dvd (Disk DVD VHP2004/16 #1, Box VHP Interview 1)
      Existence and Location of Copies note
      Interview video also available online.
      Streaming Video